<PERSON>  QA  automation  engineer  <LOCATION>,  <LOCATION>  |  <PHONE_NUMBER>  |  <EMAIL_ADDRESS>  |  LinkedIn |  Github  SUMMARY:  QA  Automation  Engineer  with  <DATE_TIME>  of  experience  in  fintech,  including  payment  systems,  ATMs,  and  
customer-facing
 
financial
 
services.
 
Strong
 
in
 
Java
 
and
 
<PERSON>,
 
with
 
solid
 
experience
 
in
 
API
 
testing
 
and
 
building
 
test
 
automation
 
frameworks.
 
Familiar
 
with
 
<PERSON>
 
and
 
<PERSON>.
 
Skilled
 
in
 
end-to-end
 
and
 
acceptance
 
testing,
 
test
 
strategy
 
development,
 
performance
 
testing
 
and
 
close
 
collaboration
 
with
 
developers.
 
Actively
 
mentor
 
QA
 
team
 
members
 
and
 
contribute
 
to
 
improving
 
testing
 
practices.
 
Comfortable
 
in
 
agile
 
teams
 
and
 
interested
 
in
 
applying
 
AI
 
tools
 
to
 
enhance
 
QA
 
processes.
 
AWS-certified.
  SKILLS:  Test  Design  |  Test  Automation  |  RESTful  API  Testing  |  UI  Testing  |  Java  |  <PERSON>  |  Performance  Testing  (Gatling)  |  
JUnit
 
|
 
TestNG
 
|
 
Git
 
|
 
SQL
 
|
 
CI/CD
 
(GitHub
 
Actions,
 
GitLab
 
CI,
 
<PERSON>)
 
|
 
Bash
 
|
 
<LOCATION>
 
|
 
Zephyr
 
(TMS)
 
|
 
Prompt
 
Engineering
 
|
 
SCRUM
 
|
 
Kanban
 
|
 
Analytical
 
Skills
 
|
 
Cross-Functional
 
Collaboration
  PROFESSIONAL  EXPERIENCE    
<LOCATION>  bank  (02.2024  –  till  now)             <LOCATION>,  <LOCATION>  Largest  fintech  in  <NRP>  <LOCATION>   Senior  QA  Automation  engineer    ●  Along  with  the  team,  improved  regression  pass  rate  from  80%  to  99%  by  implementing  automated  end-to-end  API  tests  
using
 
<PERSON>
 
and
 
JUnit
 
across
 
four
 
services.
 ●  Increased  overall  test  coverage  and  early  bug  detection  by  reducing  reliance  on  complex  E2E  tests  through  structured  
scenarios
 
for
 
low-level
 
service
 
testing.
 ●  Cut  down  cross-team  bug  triage  meetings  by  introducing  early  risk  analysis  during  test  planning.  ●  Standardized  risk  analysis  as  a  QA  practice  by  having  each  QA  lead  sessions  before  testing  new  features.  ●  Enabled  early  detection  of  performance  regressions  by  integrating  performance  tests  into  each  merge  request,  using  a  
Gatling
 
testing
 
project
 
that
 
I
 
developed
 
from
 
scratch.
 ●  Successfully  onboarded  and  mentored  the  team’s  first  junior  QA  by  creating  a  structured  learning  plan  and  offering  
hands-on
 
guidance,
 
resulting
 
in
 
her
 
becoming
 
a
 
confident
 
and
 
contributing
 
team
 
member.
 
QLess  (03.2022  –  01.2024)            <LOCATION>,  <LOCATION>-based  queue  management  and  engagement  software  QA  automation  engineer   ●  Decreased  deployment  time  by  3x  and  reduced  security  vulnerabilities  following  a  SOC  audit,  by  delivering  a  CI/CD  
migration
 
project
 
from
 
<PERSON>
 
to
 
GitHub
 
Actions.
 ●  Prevented  critical  issues  ahead  of  the  first  major  product  release  by  leading  <DATE_TIME><DATE_TIME>  crowdtesting  initiative,  
managing
 
test
 
design,
 
bug
 
triage,
 
team
 
training,
 
and
 
reporting
 
directly
 
to
 
the
 
CEO.
 ●  Enabled  development  and  tuning  of  AI  features  for  the  core  product,  by  creating  a  test  data  generation  tool  used  by  the  AI  
team
 
to
 
simulate
 
large-scale
 
data
 
scenarios,
 
and
 
also
 
adopted
 
by
 
designers
 
and
 
product
 
owners.
 
Sberbank  (11.2019  –  03.2022)               <LOCATION>,  <LOCATION>  Leading  banking  group  in  CIS  QA  automation  engineer   ●  Reduced  release  preparation  time  2x  by  establishing  QA  processes  for  requirement  validation,  acceptance  testing,  and  
release
 
management
 
in
 
a
 
new
 
team.
 ●  Improved  product  stability  by  reviewing  system  specifications,  leading  to  more  precise  documentation  from  analysts  and  
reducing
 
assumptions
 
made
 
by
 
developers.
 ●  Built  end-to-end  test  suite  and  <PERSON>  pipeline  from  scratch,  enabling  team-wide  regression  testing  and  reducing  release  
cycles
 
from
 
1.5
 
<DATE_TIME>
 
to
 
<DATE_TIME>.
 ●  Provided  secure  transaction  testing  by  setting  up  and  maintaining  Thales  HSM10k  hardware  in  the  QA  environment.  ●  Contributed  to  team  growth  by  participating  in  10  QA  interviews  and  candidate  assessments.   EDUCATION   
MATI  named  after  K.Tsiolkovsky                          <LOCATION>,  <LOCATION>  <DATE_TIME>.  Electronics  and  Computer  Engineering    CERTIFICATION/COURSES/LICENSES   Amazon  -  AWS  Solution  Architect  Associate(2026)    ADDITIONAL  INFORMATION
 
●  Languages:  <NRP>  (native),  English  (full  working  proficiency)  ●  My  technical  blog  on Medium